# Rajan Vijayan

Senior UI Developer and WordPress Technical Lead rajanit2000@gmail.com

#### **Summary**

Internet executive with over 6 years of experience which, includes HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Twitter Bootstrap responsive UI framework, Zurb foundation responsive UI framework, Hands on experience in jQuery, Decent experience VueJS and AngularJS, WordPress Plugin Creation and Theme Development, Responsive UI development, WordPress Plugin Customization.

#### **Work History**

#### Senior Software Engineer at Revmakx

Apr 2017 - present

Senior Software Engineer for the major project of Infinite WordPress Panel.

Used skills: WordPress, JQuery, Twitter Bootstrap, Vue JS

#### Senior UI Developer and WordPress Technical Lead at a2z technologies

October 2013 - Apr 2017(3 years 2 months)

Senior UI developer and WordPress Technical Lead with experience in the depth and breadth of website development with WordPress and UI Frameworks. An extensive background that includes analytics and web application projects in Woo Commerce, Web Applications and other industries for a variety of clients. Instructor and trainer in WordPress.

Used skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, WordPress, Twitter Bootstrap, Foundation

#### UI Developer at a2z technologies

October 2012 - September 2013 (1 year)

A Player for WordPress Development Team. Create WordPress Themes and Plugins with documentation. Customize the WordPress as per client's requirements.

Used skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, WordPress

#### Web Developer at The Spider India Pvt Ltd

March 2012 - October 2012 (8 months)

Junior PHP Programmer, A good team player for the small developing team to create php core projects.

Used skills: Core PHP, mySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

#### Contribution

WordPress Plugin Author at WordPress

March 2013 - Present

Create some WordPress plugins that is WP Smart Property, WP Smart Flexslider, and WP Smart Wishlist.

# Rajan Vijayan

Senior UI Developer and WordPress Technical Lead rajanit2000@gmail.com

Translation Contributor at WordPress
October 2013 - Present
Translation Contributor to WordPress Tamil.
https://make.wordpress.org/polyglots/teams/?locale=ta\_IN
WordPress on my team and I have the translations necessary for it to present in Tamil

Code Contributor at GitHub October 2012 - Present

Create starter packages for Bootstrap, WordPress basic theme and WordPress basic plugins.

#### **Publications**

WP Smart Property (WordPress Plugin)

WordPress Org June 6, 2014

Author: Rajan Vijayan

This is the Real Estate property management plugin with smart admin control and searching option and easy to modify your theme. This plugin stores properties like a post so it does not need any theme update

WP Smart Flex Slider (WordPress Plugin)

WordPress Org May 5, 2014

Author: Rajan Vijayan

This is Bootstrap Flexslider plugin. It's used for Bootstrap v3x Themes. Its have admin controls options, Navigation and Directions options in admin panel.

### Languages

English Tamil

# Skills & Expertise

WordPress, jQuery, HTML, PHP, CSS, HTML5, AJAX, VueJS, Bootstrap, JavaScript,

#### **Education**

Bachelor's degree in Information Technology GTN Arts & Science College, Information Technology, 2008 - 2011

Grade: A

# Rajan Vijayan

Senior UI Developer and WordPress Technical Lead rajanit2000@gmail.com

#### **Personal Life and Interests**

I have a cute family with a kid, Most of my the time he fights with me or play with me, and sometimes sleeping:-)

I have interest in Reading books, Facebook blogging, and Beer

#### **Contact Details**

No 9, Navamani Street, CB Colony Chrompet, Chennai - 600 044 Home: +91 909 504 2181

Personal: +91 978 914 6469

#### **Reference Links**

https://profiles.wordpress.org/rajanit2000/

https://github.com/rajanit2000

https://in.linkedin.com/in/rajanit2000